<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'
      xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'
      xml:lang='en-us'>
 <title>ongoing by Tim Bray</title>
 <link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/</id>
 <link href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/' />
 <link rel='self' href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/ongoing.atom' />
 <link rel='replies'       thr:count='101'       href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/comments.atom' />
 <logo>rsslogo.jpg</logo>
 <icon>/favicon.ico</icon>
 <updated>2017-05-23T11:55:03-07:00</updated>
 <author><name>Tim Bray</name></author>
 <subtitle>ongoing fragmented essay by Tim Bray</subtitle>
 <rights>All content written by Tim Bray and photos by Tim Bray Copyright Tim Bray, some rights reserved, see /ongoing/misc/Copyright</rights>
 <generator uri='/misc/Colophon'>Generated from XML source code using Perl, Expat, Emacs, Mysql, Ruby, Java, and ImageMagick.  Industrial-strength technology, baby.</generator>

<entry>
 <title>Rock Surprise</title>
 <link href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/05/20/Rock-Surprise' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='2'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='/ongoing/When/201x/2017/05/20/Rock-Surprise#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/05/20/Rock-Surprise</id>
 <published>2017-05-20T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2017-05-21T11:13:00-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Music' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Music' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>On a re&#xad;cent Satur&#xad;day we ac&#xad;ci&#xad;den&#xad;tal&#xad;ly took in two very dif&#xad;fer&#xad;ent pop-music con&#xad;cert&#xad;s; I got one de&#xad;cent pic but end&#xad;ed the evening an&#xad;gry.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>On a recent Saturday we accidentally took in two very
different pop-music concerts; I got one decent
pic but ended the evening angry.</p>
<p>Months ago, I’d learned that
<a href="http://www.allthemwitches.org/">All Them Witches</a> were touring and
bought Vancouver-gig tickets, because I liked the basic loud well-written
tuneful guitar-rock songs I’d heard on the radio or YouTube or somewhere.
Then Lauren looked at the calendar and said “Hey, we’ve got Bobbi’s birthday
party that night.” But it was OK because the party was early.</p>
<p>It was at the
<a href="http://www.fairviewpub.ca/">Fairview Pub</a>, which I’ve gone by on
wheels and feet a zillion times, once or twice even recognizing the name of
the bar band, but never inside.  I assumed, at 4:30, it’d be beers and
conversation.</p>
<p>But I got a couple of shocks when I walked in.  First, there was a
nine-piece horns-and-guitar soul revue tearing up <cite>Rock Steady</cite>.
Second, once my eyes adjusted, I felt… young.  Well, have a look at the
picture.</p>
<img src="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/05/20/FXT19129.png" alt="Big City Soul" />
<p>The band is
<a href="https://www.bigcitysoul.ca/">Big City Soul</a>. Not much of a
picture, and unfair because it leaves out co-lead-singer
<a href="https://www.bigcitysoul.ca/bio">Connie Ballendine</a>.</p>
<p>They’re <em>good</em>!  And the audience is <em>old</em>!  But, so am
I.</p>
<p>The waitress told me that the white-hair set comes in for the 4:30-7:30
show; then they have a rock band later, and a younger crowd.</p>
<p>So, the geezers on the dance floor were laying down some pretty sharp
moves, and the band was playing some super hot licks. Pretty straight-ahead
R&amp;B; I remember <cite>Them Changes</cite> and <cite>Good Rockin’ at
Midnight</cite>. They closed with <cite>Proud Mary</cite>, which it’s hard to
do anything new with; their approach was playing it twice as fast as anyone,
which worked OK.</p>
<p>Nothing I heard changed my life, but the band was tight and fast and
beautifully rehearsed.  Except, during a sax solo, I cracked up
because the break had <em>three bars of jazz</em> in it, which just didn’t work<span class='dashes'> —</span> remember that great
scene in <cite>The Commitments</cite>?</p>
<p>In fact, they were a lot like the Commitments,
only greying middle-class Canadians instead of snotty Dublin greasers.
Also, the sound was pretty good. I left smiling from ear to ear.</p>
<p>It didn’t
last.  All Them Witches were at Vancouver’s sleazy old
Cobalt Hotel, near the heroin neighborhood.
What a dive, except for it’s got a higher stage than most bar venues,
so you can usually see the band.</p>
<p>The opener was meh, sang out of tune and played too long.
Finally, the Witches ambled on stage and muddled through getting wired up.
I guess they’re not at a level where they have a road crew as such.</p>
<p>When they were all connected, they started
playing<span class='dashes'> —</span> the first attempt didn’t take for some
reason but they lurched into gear on the second attempt.</p>
<p>The sound was execrable, with Charles Michael Parks Jr’s vocals mixed
behind the guitars.  The songs, interspersed with lengthy
episodes of bass re-tuning, were pretty good when you could hear them.  The
dual-guitar sound occasionally bit down super-hard and just right.  But
basically, they just weren’t bringing it.</p>
<img src="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/05/20/FXT19138.png" alt="Charles Michael Parks Jr of All Them Witches" />
<img src="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/05/20/FXT19144.png" alt="Charles Michael Parks Jr of All Them Witches" />
<div class='caption'><p>Looks like a rock star, though.<br/>
Shooting live electric music with a modern camera is totally a gas.</p></div>
<p>I might even buy their recording. But that performance was a disgrace to
an honorable profession.</p>
<p>I’m not ready to start dancing to the safe stuff with the other old
people. But If you’re offering something new and fresh, you still have to come
halfway and work for your money.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry>
 <title>I Don&#x2019;t Believe in Blockchain</title>
 <link href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/05/13/Not-Believing-in-Blockchain' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='16'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='/ongoing/When/201x/2017/05/13/Not-Believing-in-Blockchain#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/05/13/Not-Believing-in-Blockchain</id>
 <published>2017-05-13T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2017-05-13T12:37:27-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Software' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Software' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>There are con&#xad;fer&#xad;ences and foun&#xad;da&#xad;tions and con&#xad;sor&#xad;tia and keynotes; it&#x2019;s the new hot&#xad;ness! But I looked in&#xad;to blockchain tech&#xad;nolo&#xad;gies care&#xad;ful&#xad;ly and I&#x2019;ve end&#xad;ed up think&#xad;ing it&#x2019;s an over&#xad;pro&#xad;mot&#xad;ed niche sideshow.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>There are conferences and foundations and consortia and keynotes; it’s
the new hotness!  But I looked into blockchain technologies carefully and I’ve
ended up thinking it’s an overpromoted niche sideshow.</p>
<p>First off, I should say that I <em>like</em> blockchain, conceptually.
Provably-immutable append-only data log with transaction validation
based on asymmetric crypto, and (optionally) a Byzantine-generals solution
too! What’s not to like?  But I still don’t think the world needs it.</p>
<p>I’m not stuck on the technical objections, for example the laughably
slow transactions-per-second of most real-world blockchain
implementations. Where I work, scaling out horizontally to support a million
TPS is table stakes.</p>
<p>I could maybe get past the socio-political issues, the misguided notion
that in civilized countries, you can route around the legal system with “smart
contracts” (in ad-hoc procedural languages) and algorithmic cryptography.</p>
<p>I could even skate around the huge business contra-indicator: Something on
the order of a billion dollars of venture-capital money has flowed into the
blockchain startup scene. And, what’s come out?  I’m not talking about
platforms that are “ready for business” or “proven enterprise-grade” or
“approved by regulatory authorities”, I’m talking about blockchain in
production with jobs depending on it.</p>
<p>But here’s the thing.  I’m an old guy: I’ve seen wave after wave of
landscape-shifting technology sweep through the IT space: Personal computers,
Unix, C, the Internet and Web, Java, REST, mobile, public cloud.
And without exception, I observed that they were initially loaded in the back
door by geeks, without asking permission, because they got shit done and
helped people with their jobs.</p>
<p>That’s not happening with blockchain.  Not in the slightest. Which is why I
don’t believe in it.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry>
 <title>Still Blogging in 2017</title>
 <link href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/05/03/Blogging-in-2017' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='19'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='/ongoing/When/201x/2017/05/03/Blogging-in-2017#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/05/03/Blogging-in-2017</id>
 <published>2017-05-03T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2017-05-03T23:38:50-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Life Online' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Life Online' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>Not alone and not un&#xad;read, but the ground un&#xad;der&#xad;foot ain&#x2019;t steady.  An in&#xad;stance of <a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homo_economicus'><i>Ho&#xad;mo eco&#xad;nomi&#xad;cus</i></a>  wouldn&#x2019;t be do&#xad;ing this<span class="dashes"> &#x2009;&#x2014;</span> &#x2009;no  pay&#xad;day loom&#xad;ing. So I guess I&#x2019;m not one of those.  But hey, when&#xad;ev&#xad;er I can steal an hour I can send the world what&#xad;ev&#xad;er  words and pic&#xad;tures oc&#xad;cu&#xad;py my mind and lap&#xad;top. Which, all these years lat&#xad;er,  still feels like im&#xad;mense priv&#xad;i&#xad;lege.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Not alone and not unread, but the ground underfoot ain’t steady.
An instance of
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homo_economicus"><i>Homo
economicus</i></a> wouldn’t be doing this<span class='dashes'> —</span> no
payday looming. So I guess I’m not one of those.
But hey, whenever I can steal an hour I can send the world whatever
words and pictures occupy my mind and laptop. Which, all these years later,
still feels like immense privilege.</p>
<p>A lot of good writing is on Medium, which has learned its bloglessons.
Shortish-to-longish form: <i>check</i>. Something fresh every day:
<i>check</i>. Follow your faves: <i>check</i>.  But on my phone, an irritating
goober at the screen’s foot says “open in app”, trying to tempt me out of the
blogosphere, off of the Web.  I guess lots of people go there but I’m not
gonna.</p>
<p>On a blog, I can write about blogging and whimsically
toss in self-indulgent pictures of May’s budding azaleas.</p>
<img src="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/05/03/FXT19074.png" alt="Budding azaleas" />
<p>I can end my career, right here, in a flash.  I can rant about the perfidy
and corruption of
<a href="https://www.bcliberals.com/">my local governing party</a>, who I
devoutly hope are about to be turfed by the voters.
I can discuss the difference between <i>O(1)</i> and <i>O(log(N))</i>, which
can usually be
safely ignored.</p>
<p>On blogs, I can read most of the long-form writing that’s worth reading
about the art
and craft of programming computers.  Or I can follow most
of the economists’ debates that are worth having. Or I can check out a new
photographer every day and see new a way of seeing the world.</p>
<p>Having said that, it seems sad that most of the traffic
these days goes to BigPubs. That the advertising dollars are being
<a href="https://twitter.com/jason_kint/status/814842452003659776">sucked inexorably
into Facebook/Google</a> and away from anyone else.  That these days, I feel
good over a piece that gets more than twenty thousand reads
(<a href="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/04/15/Camera-News">only
one</a> so far this year).</p>
<p>But I don’t care.  I’ll prove it by running a picture of a cement mixer’s
insides.</p>
<img src="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/05/03/FXT19089.png" alt="Inside a cement mixer" />
<p>I wonder what the Web will be like when we’re a couple more generations in?
I’m pretty sure that as long as it remains easy to fill a little bit of the
great namespace with your words and pictures, people will.</p>
<p>The great danger is that the Web’s future is mall-like: No space really
public, no storefronts but national brands’, no visuals composed by amateurs,
nothing that’s on offer just for its own sake, and for love.</p>
<p>Here’s a visual composed by an amateur.</p>
<img src="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/05/03/FXT19066.png" alt="New York in a rainstorm" />
<div class='caption'><p>Manhattan rainstorm (spot the bicyclist).</p></div>
<p>If you’re reading this, you have my thanks.
But let’s be honest: I can’t know what you like.  Every human product
that’s really worth reading or seeing or hearing is made mostly to please its
human producer. Because if you aim to please the world you usually miss, the
target’s just too big and you can only guess where it is..</p>
<p>That, more than anything, is why I’m still optimistic about whatever this
thing is I’m doing here.</p>
<p>Anyhow, I’m not going away.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry>
 <title>MLB Fan</title>
 <link href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/04/29/MLB-Fan' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='1'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='/ongoing/When/201x/2017/04/29/MLB-Fan#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/04/29/MLB-Fan</id>
 <published>2017-04-29T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2017-05-01T14:36:01-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Sports/Baseball' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Sports' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Baseball' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Business/Internet' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Business' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Internet' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>I was in New York last week, and got to make  a call on <a href='http://www.mlbam.com/'>MLBAM</a>, a re&#xad;al&#xad;ly smart  cus&#xad;tomer of AWS, where I work.  The first three let&#xad;ters in MLBAM mean base&#xad;bal&#xad;l, of which I&#x2019;m  a <a href='/ongoing/What/Sports/Baseball'>devo&#xad;tee</a>; and al&#xad;so a hap&#xad;py  five-year sub&#xad;scrib&#xad;ing cus&#xad;tomer of <a href='http://mlb.tv/'>MLB.tv</a>. So I was feel&#xad;ing sort of multi-level fan&#xad;nish. It was super-fun, and I got a cute pic&#xad;ture.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>I was in New York last week, and got to make
a call on <a href="http://www.mlbam.com/">MLBAM</a>, a really smart
customer of AWS, where I work.
The first three letters in MLBAM mean baseball, of which I’m
a <a href="/ongoing/What/Sports/Baseball">devotee</a>; and also a happy
five-year subscribing customer of <a href="http://mlb.tv/">MLB.tv</a>. So I
was feeling sort of multi-level fannish. It was super-fun, and I got a cute picture.</p>
<p>MLB’s in a nice corner of SoHo and the offices are drop-dead cool, although
I suspect the bobblehead-and-memorabilia density might be a bit much for some.</p>
<p>Anyhow, while you’re waiting in the lobby you can admire their fine
selection of trophies, a lot of them tech-geek stuff.  But there’s at least
one Emmy, and then have a close look at the one in the middle.</p>
<img src="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/04/29/LRM_20170425_122412.png" alt="Trophies at the MLB.com office" />
<div class='caption'><p>The little plaque says:<br/><i>NYC Metro Sports<br/>
2008 Co-Ed Softball<br/>
Division 3 Metro Champions<br/>
MLB.COM</i></p></div>
<p>There were at least two of those NYC-city championship
trophies, and I suspect that’s pretty elite amateur-ball territory.
What I’d call walking the talk.</p>
<p>A footnote, by the way: I’ve had MLB as a customer before, at Sun,
pre-cloud. Sometime around the time they won that NYC trophy
they took me out to an Oakland game. I got to sit in the press-box and it
stands out in my memory because the visiting team was Seattle, and also in
that box were the cheery and deranged Japanese press gaggle who followed
Ichiro around to all his games, back then.</p>
<p>Anyhow, if you like baseball at all, I totally recommend subscribing to
their service. It Just Works, and on just about every conceivable device with
a screen or a speaker, with lots of polish and attention to detail.</p>
<p>It makes me happy that they’re using software that I helped write, and
it’s a signal of their sophistication that they’re well into adopting stuff I
was still coding late last year.</p>
<p>They’re generally just damn smart in the way they use the cloud, to the
extent that they’re now doing Internet for a growing list of other sports.</p>
<p>In particular, I got a briefing on the machinery they’ve put together to
get all that
<a href="http://mlb.mlb.com/stats/sortable.jsp#elem=%5Bobject+Object%5D&amp;tab_level=child&amp;click_text=Sortable+Player+hitting&amp;game_type='R'&amp;season=2017&amp;season_type=ANY&amp;league_code='MLB'&amp;sectionType=sp&amp;statType=hitting&amp;page=1&amp;ts=1493531097157">Statcast</a>
raw data out of the parks and into the Internet. It included a couple of
jaw-droppers, and there might be a chance to pitch in with some stuff we’re
just coding up right now.</p>
<p>Anyhow, thanks to ’em for hosting us, and I wish we’d scheduled another
hour or two.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry>
 <title>Six-page Typography</title>
 <link href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/04/23/Six-page-Typography' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='6'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='/ongoing/When/201x/2017/04/23/Six-page-Typography#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/04/23/Six-page-Typography</id>
 <published>2017-04-23T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2017-04-23T21:34:38-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Publishing' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Publishing' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>What hap&#xad;pened was, Lau&#xad;ren brought home Bringhurst&#x2019;s <a href='http://amzn.to/2ojqod6'>The Ele&#xad;ments of Ty&#xad;po&#xad;graph&#xad;ic Style</a>  and I was  in&#xad;stant&#xad;ly cap&#xad;ti&#xad;vat&#xad;ed, by the book&#x2019;s beau&#xad;ty and al&#xad;so the pow&#xad;er of its  mes&#xad;sage. So I&#x2019;ve got ty&#xad;pog&#xad;ra&#xad;phy on my mind. Stand by for more on the sub&#xad;jec&#xad;t,  but it struck me im&#xad;me&#xad;di&#xad;ate&#xad;ly that I&#x2019;m liv&#xad;ing a ty&#xad;pog&#xad;ra&#xad;phy les&#xad;son at work,  in the form of the fa&#xad;mous Ama&#xad;zon six-pager.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>What happened was, Lauren brought home Bringhurst’s
<a href="http://amzn.to/2ojqod6">The Elements of Typographic Style</a> and I was
instantly captivated, by the book’s beauty and also the power of its
message. So I’ve got typography on my mind. Stand by for more on the subject,
but it struck me immediately that I’m living a typography lesson at work,
in the form of the famous Amazon six-pager.</p>
<p>It’s not a secret; to start with, read Brad Porter’s excellent
<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/beauty-amazons-6-pager-brad-porter">The
Beauty of Amazon’s 6-Pager</a> (although in typo-geek mode, I have to point
out that “Six-pager” reads much more nicely than “6-Pager”).</p>
<p>Like Brad says, we put intense work into writing these things, and then
others of us put intense work into reading them. I’m at a place in the
structure where I find myself doing both;  neither is easier than the other.</p>
<p>As a guy who’s invested years into
<a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2003/04/09/SemanticMarkup">descriptive markup</a> and
structured documents and flexible presentation and so on, I ought to be
horrified by six-pagers, which are fixed-format paginated word-processor
output.  But in fact they work great.  It saves so much time when you can say
“That replication setup, second para on page 3, won’t it murder write
throughput?”</p>
<p>You know what I’m starting to see?  People putting in line numbers.  And
that’s an even bigger time-saver, particularly if you want to raise an issue
about how <em>this</em> on page 1 relates to <em>that</em> on page 5.</p>
<p>Oh, and we do some initial reviewing electronically, but when
it matters, six-pagers are printed.  Because of course.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry>
 <title>2017 Camera News</title>
 <link href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/04/15/Camera-News' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='7'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='/ongoing/When/201x/2017/04/15/Camera-News#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/04/15/Camera-News</id>
 <published>2017-04-15T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2017-04-16T15:24:40-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos/Cameras' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Cameras' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>Here&#xad;with some re&#xad;portage on the most in&#xad;ter&#xad;est&#xad;ing cam&#xad;eras in the world, with opin&#xad;ions to pro&#xad;voke er en&#xad;ter&#xad;tain peo&#xad;ple who are up on this stuff, and a ba&#xad;sic sur&#xad;vey of the land&#xad;scape for peo&#xad;ple who like pic&#xad;tures and won&#xad;der about cam&#xad;eras.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Herewith some reportage on the most interesting cameras in the world, with
opinions to provoke er entertain people who are up on this stuff, and a basic
survey of the landscape for people who like pictures and wonder about
cameras.</p>
<p><i>[Update]:</i> The same day I wrote this, DPReview ran a nice piece on
<a href="https://www.dpreview.com/videos/7871708444/ask-the-staff-cherry-blossoms">shooting Seattle cherry blossoms with a bunch of different cameras</a>, including
a few of the types, and individual cameras, discussed here.  Check it out.</p>
<p>I’m an
<a href="/ongoing/What/Arts/Photos/">enthusiast
photog</a> (not remotely pro) and I’ve noticed, over the years, when I write
generally about what’s up with cameras, I get notes from people saying
“thanks, that was interesting”.  I think I may have sold a few cameras over
the years, even.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Conclusions first</h2>
<p>Let’s see if we can start some arguments.</p>
<ol>
<li><p>The most interesting cameras in the world right now are the new digital
“medium formats”:
<a href="https://www.dpreview.com/reviews/fujifilm-gfx-50s">Fujifilm GFX 50S</a>,
<a href="https://luminous-landscape.com/pentax-645z-in-depth-review/">Pentax
645Z</a>, and
<a href="https://www.dpreview.com/reviews/hasselblad-x1d-50c">Hasselblad
X1D</a>.
Here’s a <a href="https://www.dpreview.com/articles/9372980153/fujifilm-gfx-50s-vs-pentax-645z-vs-hasselblad-x1d">comparo.</a>
But they’re expensive and you almost certainly don’t need one unless you’re a
pro.</p></li>
<li><p>The next most interesting cameras in the world are the
<a href="https://www.google.ca/webhp?sourceid=chrome-instant&amp;ion=1&amp;espv=2&amp;ie=UTF-8#q=better+camera+pixel+or+iphone">ones in mobile
phones</a>.  They’re excellent for most things, but don’t obsolete “real”
cameras just yet.</p></li>
<li><p>All modern cameras take great pictures. The most important differences
between them are ergonomic: How quickly and easily you can get the shot,
especially when conditions are bad.</p></li>
<li><p>There are reasons to think that the “APS-C” and “full-frame” sensors
are the big winners going forward; the price of being smaller, and the cost of
being larger, are both too high.</p></li>
<li><p>I think the SLR is probably doomed; mirrorless cameras have
too many advantages.</p></li>
</ol>
<p>Picture break!  The theme is spring.</p>
<img src="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/04/15/LRM_20170413_182847.png" alt="Spring blossoms" />
<h2 id='p-2'>Camera taxonomy</h2>
<p>You can sort cameras into two baskets; by how big their sensor is, and
by their physical configuration.  For sensors, bigger is better; sizes that are
relevant today, small to large,  are:</p>
<ol>
<li><p><i>1/2.3"</i> (7.7mm diagonal, more or less); this is what good modern
phone-cams
have.</p></li>
<li><p><i>Micro Four Thirds</i> (~21.5mm diagonal); what the mirrorless cameras from Olympus and
Panasonic have.</p></li>
<li><p><i>APS-C</i> (~28mm); what most “ordinary” DSLRs, and the Fujifilm/Sony mirrorlesses,
have.</p></li>
<li><p><i>Full Frame</i> (~43mm); what’s
in the Canon, Nikon, and Sony flagships.</p></li>
<li><p><i>Medium Format</i> (~55mm); also called 645, A.K.A. <em>really freaking
big</em>. This is what the “most interesting cameras” at #1 in the first list
above use; interesting because they have these sensors in bodies, and at price
points, that are not totally out of reach.</p></li>
</ol>
<p>There’s a pretty good write-up on all these size trade-offs at
<a href="http://newatlas.com/camera-sensor-size-guide/26684/">Camera sensor
size: Why does it matter and exactly how big are they?</a> But it’s from 2013
and doesn’t include Medium Format.</p>
<p>As for configurations, three are interesting these days.</p>
<ol>
<li><p>Mobile phone; it fits in your pocket and you shoot by tapping on the
screen.</p></li>
<li><p>SLR; the most “traditional” shape, with a lump on the top, and you look
out through the front lens with the help of prisms and mirrors.</p></li>
<li><p>Mirrorless; you look at an electronic reproduction of what the camera sensor is
seeing, either through a viewfinder or a screen on the back of the camera.
Those “most interesting” medium format cameras are interesting partly because
two of them are mirrorless; the Pentax is the only SLR.</p>
</li>
</ol>

<p>Time for another picture break!</p>
<img src="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/04/15/FXT19029.png" alt="Sprint moss" />
<h2 id='p-3'>How big a sensor do you need?</h2>
<p>The little ones in your phone can take great pictures; why would you want
more?  Two big reasons: A bigger sensor makes it easier to get that
nice effect where your subject is sharp and the background is fuzzy (see the
sharp fuzzball below). Second,
if you have more pixels you can blow your picture up bigger, for example to
print and hang on a wall.</p>
<p>The first argument is good, but the second is weak.  Because most of us,
these days, share and enjoy pictures on screens, and only on screens.
That blossoms-and-sky pic at
the top came out of my Google Pixel and, <em>after cropping</em>, is
2764×3375.  My 15" Retina MacBook Pro only has 1200 pixels of vertical
resolution. So I already can’t display all the pixels from my Pixel.</p>
<p>Also, on the wall of my living room I have a
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2012/09/06/The-Big-Picture">four-foot-tall
print</a> of a photo shot with an old-school pocket cam (no longer relevant in
the mobile-cam era)
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2012/08/15/Dreampeaks">from an airplane</a>.</p>
<p>So, it’s surprising how big you can go.  But still… last time I was in Vegas I
went wandering and ended up at
<a href="http://www.rodneyloughjr.com/">Rodney Lough’s gallery</a>, full of
room-size blow-ups; I found many of them overwrought and overproduced, but
wow, the impact is not to be denied. He’s still using 4×5" and 8×10"
film cameras, but I bet those medium-format puppies at #1 above could do the
trick.</p>
<p>Realistically though, are you going to want to work with pictures wider
than you are tall?</p>
<p>Picture break!</p>
<img src="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/04/15/FXT18996.png" alt="Left over from last fall" />
<h2 id='p-4'>So what really matters?</h2>
<p>For most practical purposes, your phonecam will meet your photographic
needs. Which is to say, the quality of your pictures will depend mostly on
your ability to see the opportunities.</p>
<p>Things your phone still can’t do: Take pictures of things that are a long
way away; capture the classic portrait look (but Apple’s working on that);
shoot in the dark (but late last year I managed to
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2016/11/12/Pixel-Abuse">capture actual
moonbeams</a> with my Pixel); have fun with different kind of lenses; take
pictures in a rainstorm.
Or (most important) let you take control of
your photographs.</p>
<p>So given that any modern camera can do all the things that your phone
can’t, and produce beautiful pictures, what are the difference that
matter?</p>
<p>It
turns out that the camera companies have (differing) opinions about how
pictures should be taken, and ship opinionated cameras.  Which is wonderful.
Personally, I’m a Fujifilm fanboy, for exactly one reason: I
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2013/10/18/Fufifilm-X-E1#p-2">like where the
knobs and dials are</a>, and how they work, and how things look through the
viewfinder.  I suppose I could get used to another maker’s opinion, but at the
moment I’m pretty convinced that <em>for me</em>, the Fujifilm setup lets me
shoot faster and focus sharper and light-compensate better.</p>
<p>There are lots of people who are going to find themselves in better tune
with the opinions of Nikon or Canon or Sony, and that’s just fine; although I
have to confess that the few times I’ve tried out a recent Sony it felt like I
was fighting against the controls, not working with them.</p>
<p>So, I’m gonna say, if you’re thinking about a camera, don’t waste time
worrying about pixels or sensors or ISOs or, really, any specs at all.  Borrow
or rent a few different ones and take some damn pictures already; then you’ll
know.</p>
<h2 id='p-5'>Focus on fun</h2>
<p>I don’t get paid for taking picture (well,
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2011/10/01/Architecture-of-Theology">rarely</a>)
and you probably don’t either, so we should bear in mind that this is a
<em>recreational</em> activity.</p>
<p>It’s a path I haven’t been down, but
I suspect the cameras that win on the pure-fun metric are
the fixed-lens mirrorless offerings, notably the Fuji
<a href="http://amzn.to/2ozfAVo">XF-100</a> or
<a href="http://amzn.to/2oiIOpJ">Leica Q</a>.  These things are kind of
expensive, but they have great lenses and great viewfinders and look cool and
if you point them at pretty well anything and shoot, you’ll probably be
happy.  Photography should make you happy.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry>
 <title>JSONPath</title>
 <link href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/04/14/JsonPath-Needs-Work' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='6'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='/ongoing/When/201x/2017/04/14/JsonPath-Needs-Work#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/04/14/JsonPath-Needs-Work</id>
 <published>2017-04-14T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2017-04-14T11:36:53-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Internet' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Internet' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>Or should be that be JsonPath? What&#xad;ev&#xad;er, it&#x2019;s a tool I&#x2019;ve been us&#xad;ing late&#xad;ly and gen&#xad;er&#xad;al&#xad;ly like. But it could use a lit&#xad;tle work.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Or should be that be JsonPath?
Whatever, it’s a tool I’ve been using lately and generally like.
But it could use a little work.</p>
<p>The last project I worked on,
<a href="https://aws.amazon.com/step-functions/">Step Functions</a>, has a
<a href="https://states-language.net/spec.html">JSON DSL</a> for State
Machines, which makes use of JSONPath (see
<a href="https://states-language.net/spec.html#path">Paths</a> and
<a href="https://states-language.net/spec.html#filters">Input and Output
Procesing</a>) to solve a tricky problem in a way that people seem to find
easy to understand and use.</p>
<p>Early on in that project we adopted the
<a href="https://github.com/json-path/JsonPath">Jayway JsonPath</a> library
and it seems to mostly Just Work.</p>
<p>But, we’ve had a few questions from customer along the lines of “Your
service rejected my InputPath, but it looks OK to me.”</p>
<p>Which raises the question: What is a legal JsonPath, anyhow?</p>
<p>To the extent there’s an “official” definition, the most obvious candidate
would be Stefan Goessner’s
<a href="http://goessner.net/articles/JsonPath/">JSONPath - XPath for
JSON</a>.  Standards wonks will sneer at it, not a shred of BNF in sight.  But
I like it, because it applies the most important lesson from Mark Pilgrim’s immortal
<a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20051016203842/http://diveintomark.org/archives/2004/08/16/specs">Morons
and Assholes</a> essay: Have lots of examples.</p>
<p>Having said that, it’s kind of skinny.  And if you go back to that
<a href="https://github.com/json-path/JsonPath">Jayway JsonPath</a> spec and
start scrolling the README.md, well, you can keep scrolling and scrolling, and
there’s a lot of goodness there.</p>
<p>But still, is <code>$.blog-entry</code> a valid JSONPath?  Or should you
have to say <code>$['blog-entry']</code>?  Because <i>blog-entry</i> is not,
after all, a JavaScript “Name” construct.</p>
<p>For the purposes of AWS Step Functions, JsonPath means what Jayway says it
means. But I’d be happier if there were an RFC or something because, good as
Jayway is, people do <i>[*gasp*]</i> write code in languages other than
Java.</p>
<p>So, an RFC maybe?  The idea’s not crazy.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Capitalization</h2>
<p>Let me settle one dispute right here: Stefan Goessner says “JSONPath”, Jayway
says “JsonPath”.  Stefan’s right, because it’s called JSON not Json, and by
the analogy with XPath.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry>
 <title>IsItOnAWS Lessons</title>
 <link href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/29/Is-it-on-AWS' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='5'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/29/Is-it-on-AWS#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/29/Is-it-on-AWS</id>
 <published>2017-03-29T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2017-03-29T23:56:46-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Cloud' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Cloud' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Web' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Web' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>I did some <a href='https://github.com/awslabs/IsItOnAWS'>recre&#xad;ation&#xad;al pro&#xad;gram&#xad;ming</a>  over Christ&#xad;mas and the blog I wrote   about it is now <a href='https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/is-it-on-aws-domain-identification-using-aws-lambda/'>guest&#xad;ing in Jeff Barr&#x2019;s space</a>    for your amuse&#xad;men&#xad;t; try the soft&#xad;ware at <a href='https://isitonaws.com'>IsItOnAWS.&#xad;com</a>. What I didn&#x2019;t do there was re&#xad;lay the lessons I picked up along the way; one or two are around AWS, but most fol&#xad;low from this be&#xad;ing my first non&#xad;triv&#xad;ial ex&#xad;pe&#xad;di&#xad;tion in&#xad;to the land of NodeJS. So (ac&#xad;knowl&#xad;edg&#xad;ing that on&#xad;ly 0.8% of my pro&#xad;fes&#xad;sion aren&#x2019;t al&#xad;ready Nodester&#xad;s), here they are. Spoil&#xad;er: I don&#x2019;t like Node very much.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>I did some
<a href="https://github.com/awslabs/IsItOnAWS">recreational programming</a> over Christmas and the blog I wrote
about it is now
<a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/is-it-on-aws-domain-identification-using-aws-lambda/">guesting in Jeff Barr’s space</a>
for your amusement; try the software at
<a href="https://isitonaws.com">IsItOnAWS.com</a>.
What I didn’t do there was relay the lessons I picked up
along the way; one or two are around AWS, but most follow from this being my
first nontrivial expedition into the land of NodeJS. So (acknowledging that only 0.8% of my
profession aren’t already Nodesters), here they are.
Spoiler: I don’t like Node very much.</p>
<p><span class="lesson">Lesson:</span> Lambda has historically been used for
behind-the-scenes work.  But with the recent arrival of new
<a href="https://aws.amazon.com/api-gateway/">API Gateway</a> and
<a href="https://aws.amazon.com/certificate-manager/">Certificate
Manager</a> goodies, it’s become pretty easy to convince a function to serve
HTTP requests pointed at your own web-space.  Will this be a popular idiom?
Beats me.</p>
<hr/>
<p><span class="lesson">Lesson:</span> I can now work with Node’s
everything-is-a-callback worldview, but still, at the end of the day I think it’s
wrong.  What I want to do is fetch data, then process
data, then write data, and if a damn computer language can’t give
me a sequential abstraction when I want to do sequential things, well
screw it.</p>
<p>Yeah, I acknowledge the kozmick performance gains Node
achieves, even when living in a single-threaded environment, by pushing
developers into callback-or-die territory, but you know, there are things
like pre-emptive multitasking and thread pools that should let the system
interleave IO and compute for performance without making me worry my pretty
little head over it.</p>
<p>Having said that, async/waterfall is a straightforward way to
remediate the damage.</p>
<hr/>
<p><span class="lesson">Lesson:</span> Node provides a very
serviceable little JavaScript REPL on my Mac.  There is no programmer on whose
life JavaScript doesn’t impinge sometimes, and a command line is awfully
helpful in exploring array combinatorics and related weirdness.js.</p>
<hr/>
<p><span class="lesson">Lesson:</span> Constructing a zip was pretty easy with
<a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/jszip">jszip</a>. Except for, despite
the fact that a zip is a bunch of bytes, jszip insisted on emitting a
<a href="https://nodejs.org/api/stream.html">Node Stream</a>.  But it seems
that NPM generally contains correctives for its misfeatures, in this case
<a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/raw-body">raw-body</a>.</p>
<hr/>
<p><span class="lesson">Lesson:</span> Node’s HTTP-fetch
function is kind of dumb and clumsy.  Every language should have a one-liner
that says “Here’s a URL, gimme back an object with the content-type and the
response body’s bytes, or let me know if you can’t.”  Of the languages I’ve
used in recent years, only Go and Ruby do.</p>
<hr/>
<p><span class="lesson">Lesson:</span> Upon publishing this,
I will receive much pitying feedback along the lines of “Well <em>of
course</em> you could have done it in a one-liner using
TheNewHotness.js.”  And also pointing out many other better ways to have
done this using things my Internet search skills were insufficiently
advanced to discover. Draw your own conclusion.</p>
<hr/>
<p><span class="lesson">Lesson:</span> The IPv6 address-literal
syntax is <a href="https://www.zerotier.com/blog/?p=724">stupidly
human-hostile</a>.</p>
<hr/>
<p><span class="lesson">Lesson:</span> NPM has at least one of
everything you can possibly imagine.</p>
<hr/>
<p><span class="lesson">Lesson:</span> NPM dependencies are a
fulminating cancerous mess.  This little Lambda that runs when the JSON
updates needs <em>fifteen freaking megabytes</em> in its node_module
directory, and the zip is like 2.5M.
For the little function that actually handles the IsItOnAWS requests, I
consciously tried to keep the dependencies down, but I still ended up
needing <a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/async">async</a>,
<a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/ipaddr.js">ipaddr.js</a>
<a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/lodash">lodash</a>, and
<a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/sprintf-js">sprintf-js</a>
for another 2½ meg.
Feaugh.  What’s a “lodash”, anyhow?</p>
<hr/>
<p><span class="lesson">Lesson:</span> The Lambda and S3 APIs
are minimal, sensible, and well-integrated into Node’s
resistence-is-futile you-will-learn-to-love-callbacks paradigm.</p>
<hr/>
<p><span class="lesson">Lesson:</span> The best Node code is
<a href="https://github.com/yoshuawuyts/tiny-guide-to-non-fancy-node/blob/master/README.md">Non
Fancy Node</a>.</p>
<hr/>
<p><span class="lesson">Lesson:</span> The
<a href="https://github.com/substack/tape">tape</a> unit-test
harness Just Worked for me out of the box, had a nearly-zero learning
curve, and was minimally intrusive. I’m a fan.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry>
 <title>Contradictions</title>
 <link href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/27/Contradictions' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='5'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/27/Contradictions#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/27/Contradictions</id>
 <published>2017-03-27T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2017-03-27T23:39:36-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Politics' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Politics' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>Back when <a href='/ongoing/When/200x/2005/05/01/May-1'>I was an ac&#xad;tu&#xad;al Marx&#xad;ist</a>, we used to talk about the &#x201c;contradictions of capitalism&#x201d;. It&#x2019;s ac&#xad;tu&#xad;al&#xad;ly a handy phrase (al&#xad;lit&#xad;er&#xad;a&#xad;tive too!) and re&#xad;cent&#xad;ly I feel like the In&#xad;ter&#xad;net is try&#xad;ing to stuff those con&#xad;tra&#xad;dic&#xad;tions down my throat.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Back when
<a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2005/05/01/May-1">I was an actual Marxist</a>, we used to talk about the
“contradictions of capitalism”.  It’s actually a handy phrase (alliterative
too!) and recently I feel like the Internet
is trying to stuff those contradictions down my throat.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Fish in a barrel</h2>
<p>It’s not exactly hard to reel them off.  <i>Item:</i> The owners of every
business are incented to pay their employees as little as possible, but need
their customers to have spare money in their pockets.  <i>Item:</i> Prosperity
depends on growth, everyone knows that; but we’re using our ecosystem fully
and population curves around the world range from flattening growth to
steepening decline.</p>
<p>See how easy it is?</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>Engagement in the clouds</h2>
<p>Two pieces crossed my radar recently.  First, Gartner recently released its annual
<a href="http://www.gallup.com/reports/199961/state-american-workplace-report-2017.aspx">State
of the American Workplace</a> report, a weighty slab of PDF you have to trade
your email address for, but
there’s a decent
<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/5-reasons-why-gallup-believes-workplace-leadership-demands-crowley">summary with some
graphs</a> over on LinkedIn.</p>
<p>The news isn’t good. It turns out
that that only about 30% of American employees are “engaged”; of the rest, 50%
or so are “disengaged” and 16% are “actively disengaged”.  And there’s loads
of quantitative data to show that lack of engagement correlates with lack of
growth, profits, and other good-biz metrics.</p>
<p>Put another way: Scott Adams may be
an annoying weaselly troll, but <cite>Dilbert</cite> is accurate
reportage.</p>
<p>Now cast your eyes at
<a href="http://avc.com/2017/02/the-future-of-labor/">The Future Of Labor</a>
by Fred Wilson, New York VC and Thought Leader; he discusses “three big
megatrends impacting the future of labor/work”, one of which is “ the move to
an on demand model for work”.  He envisions a future where, when a business
needs something done, “they issue the work order to the labor cloud and
someone picks up the work order and gets it done.”  This allows the business
“to get the work done without thinking about the kind of relationship they
have with the worker.”</p>
<p>Obviously, no sane manager should expect “engagement” from the denizens of
the “labor cloud”, any more than they can from the growing chunk of the
population working for low pay in permanent-part-time mode.  See?
Contradiction!</p>
<h2 id='p-3'>Hunger</h2>
<p>You want <em>real</em> contradiction?  How about
<a href="https://www.dosomething.org/facts/11-facts-about-hunger-us">11 Facts
About Hunger in the US</a>.  The US, you know, Earth’s richest nation. Where
17.5 million households are “food insecure”.</p>
<p>I don’t miss Marxism as a framework, but let’s not kid ourselves that the
symptoms it was trying to address are behind us.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry>
 <title>Garage Color Fix</title>
 <link href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/21/Garage-Color' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='3'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/21/Garage-Color#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/21/Garage-Color</id>
 <published>2017-03-21T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2017-03-21T19:24:16-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>I was out the oth&#xad;er day <a href='/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/18/Prairie-Spring'>shoot&#xad;ing signs of spring</a>; there was this garage, and it was pret&#xad;ty too.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>I was out the other day
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/18/Prairie-Spring">shooting signs of
spring</a>; there was this garage, and it was pretty too.</p>
<img src="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/21/garage-fixed.png" alt="Regina, Saskatchewan garage in color-corrected light turquoise" />
<div class='caption'><p>Color partly by some paint company, augmented by
<br/>quite a few years of Prairie weather.  Isn’t it pretty?</p></div>
<p>The reason I’m writing this is that it’s the first time in years I’ve had
to put significant work into color repair on a Fujifilm pic.
Because the version above looks just like what I saw. But out of
the camera, it looked like this:</p>
<img src="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/21/garage-fixed-2.png" alt="Regina, Saskatchewan garage in light turquoise, no color correction" />
<p>Back in my Pentax days, I got pretty slick with the Lightroom
white-balance apparatus, which is itself pretty slick.  But in my four
Fujifilm years I’m not sure I’ve touched them.</p>
<p>Well, I did on that one. It didn’t work; I found another way:</p>
<ol>
<li><p>White balance: as shot.</p></li>
<li><p>Exposure: -0.25 (fight that glare).</p></li>
<li><p>Highlights: -15 (fight some more).</p></li>
<li><p>Shadows: +10 (boost the shady side).</p></li>
<li><p>Saturation: +33 (the colors weren’t <em>wrong</em>, they were just
washed-out).</p></li>
<li><p>Blue: -20 (sky was overexcited).
At this point things were better but still not what I’d seen.
Time for the secret weapon.</p></li>
<li><p>Profile: Velvia/VIVID (smiles).</p></li>
</ol>
<p>I don’t know who it was at Fujifilm and Adobe that got those film
treatments into Lightroom, but I sure owe them thanks.  I don’t use one that
often, but so great to have it.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry>
 <title>Prairie Spring</title>
 <link href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/18/Prairie-Spring' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='1'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/18/Prairie-Spring#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/18/Prairie-Spring</id>
 <published>2017-03-18T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2017-03-18T09:44:18-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Places/Saskatchewan' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Places' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Saskatchewan' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>Most places know four sea&#xad;son&#xad;s, but for the most in&#xad;tense ex&#xad;pe&#xad;ri&#xad;ence of spring you re&#xad;al&#xad;ly come Up North. I&#x2019;m in Saskatchewan vis&#xad;it&#xad;ing my Mom, went for a short walk in the park be&#xad;hind her house, and came back with pic&#xad;tures of the ex&#xad;pe&#xad;ri&#xad;ence.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Most places know four seasons, but for the most intense experience of
spring you really come Up North. I’m in Saskatchewan
visiting my Mom, went for a short walk in the park behind her house, and came
back with pictures of the experience.</p>
<p>Most obviously, the snow is retreating.</p>
<img src="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/18/FXT18982.png" alt="Prairie spring - retreating snow" />
<p>With the melting and freezing of early spring, some of the snow is now
crumbly puddled ice, which is melting in the cold March sun, and faster given
an excuse.</p>
<img src="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/18/FXT18987.png" alt="Leaf melts spring ice in the prairie spring" />
<p>An excuse for a little Physics Moment with my
ten-year-old: “Hey girl, why did the ice melt over the leaf?”</p>
<p>But that ice is being attacked from below as above; see the blades of grass
straining away?  Some green is already showing.</p>
<img src="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/18/FXT18990.png" alt="Prairie ice melting in spring" />
<p>That ice, it’s a treat for the eye as it melts.</p>
<img src="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/18/FXT18993.png" alt="Melting snow on the prairies in spring" />
<p>Having said that, it’s still not much above 0°C and there’s a brisk wind.
But at 50.45° N, the oncoming spring is not to be denied.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry>
 <title>Whiteboard Interviews</title>
 <link href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/04/Whiteboard-Interviews' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='8'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/04/Whiteboard-Interviews#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/03/04/Whiteboard-Interviews</id>
 <published>2017-03-04T12:00:00-08:00</published>
 <updated>2017-03-04T11:51:02-08:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>The oth&#xad;er day, I joined a semi-viral tweet chain with <a href='https://twitter.com/timbray/status/836009408131837952'>I&#x2019;ve been cod&#xad;ing since 1979 and I still have to look up java.lang.String meth&#xad;ods all the time.</a>  There were a bunch of pro&#xad;gram&#xad;mers do&#xad;ing this and I thought it   con&#xad;sti&#xad;tut&#xad;ed amus&#xad;ing hu&#xad;mil&#xad;i&#xad;ty while al&#xad;so mak&#xad;ing a use&#xad;ful point: Re&#xad;mem&#xad;ber&#xad;ing the   de&#xad;tails of any par&#xad;tic&#xad;u&#xad;lar API or al&#xad;go&#xad;rithm is ir&#xad;rel&#xad;e&#xad;van&#xad;t. Turns out I was   part of a trend, see <cite>TheOut&#xad;line</cite>: <a href='https://theoutline.com/post/1166/programmers-are-confessing-their-coding-sins-to-protest-a-broken-job-interview-process'>Pro&#xad;gram&#xad;mers Are Con&#xad;fess&#xad;ing Their Cod&#xad;ing Sins to Protest a Bro&#xad;ken Job In&#xad;ter&#xad;view Pro&#xad;cess</a>. Ex&#xad;cept for, that&#x2019;s bull&#xad;shit; I still do white&#xad;boards at in&#xad;ter&#xad;views, and I don&#x2019;t think the idea is bro&#xad;ken. (Al&#xad;so, they&#x2019;re not sin&#xad;s.)</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>The other day, I joined a semi-viral tweet chain with
<a href="https://twitter.com/timbray/status/836009408131837952">I’ve been
coding since 1979 and I still have to look up java.lang.String methods all the
time.</a> There were a bunch of programmers doing this and I thought it
constituted amusing humility while also making a useful point: Remembering the
details of any particular API or algorithm is irrelevant.  Turns out I was
part of a trend, see <cite>TheOutline</cite>:
<a href="https://theoutline.com/post/1166/programmers-are-confessing-their-coding-sins-to-protest-a-broken-job-interview-process">Programmers Are Confessing Their Coding Sins to Protest a Broken Job Interview Process</a>.
Except for, that’s bullshit; I still do whiteboards at interviews, and I don’t
think the idea is broken. (Also, they’re not sins.)</p>
<p>Does this mean I ask people to code a bubble sort?  Or to show any evidence
that they remember the details of any particular API?  Obviously not: As many
have pointed out, that’s what Wikipedia, StackOverflow, and (most often) my
IDE’s auto-complete are for.</p>
<p>These days, when I’m interviewing for senior-developer and
development-manager positions at AWS, my questions are of the form “Design X”,
where X is something like Twitter or SQS.  The whiteboard is an
appropriate level of detail; I want to look at the boxes and arrows they
draw and see if they come up with a sane decomposition of the problem, and if they spot
where the hard parts are.  Sometimes, if there’s enough time, I might ask them
to sketch in a bit of front-end code, but usually not.</p>
<p>Back when I was at Google, I was mostly interviewing people for “Developer
Advocate” positions, and a lot of people somehow got into the process without
being able to code at all.  So, early on, I’d ask.  “You’ve got a list of
objects, write some code to select one of them at random. Any language, don’t
worry about syntax, assume the built-in random function is good enough.”</p>
<p>That was actually a nice question: If you wanted to dive a little deeper,
you could ask the candidate to sketch in unit tests.  And if you’re talking to
somebody super-technical, ask
“Your code is in production and sometimes it’s throwing
illegal-index exceptions under heavy load. What’s going on and how do you fix
it?”  Just because that’s a cool problem, very real-life, and most people
smile when they get it.</p>
<p>Apparently DHH started the trend by admitting he couldn’t code a bubble
sort on a whiteboard, and I think we can all agree that would be a totally
dorky interview question. But TheOutline’s piece goes further, alleging that
whiteboarding is anti-diversity.  See
<a href="https://twitter.com/alinelernerLLC">Aline Lerner</a>’s excellent
(and data-rich)
<a href="http://blog.interviewing.io/you-cant-fix-diversity-in-tech-without-fixing-the-technical-interview/">You can’t fix diversity in tech without fixing the technical interview.</a>
It mostly argues that “logic puzzle” interview questions are bullshit, and I
heartily agree.  By the way I got one of those in my interview day at Google, and
another at Amazon, and I blew them both.</p>
<p>At AWS, these days, I’m on a few hiring loops, and I don’t see anyone
asking logic puzzles.  But I have no idea what the state of the art is these
days at the big tech companies; are there any studies?</p>
<p>I think and hope that the way I use the whiteboard doesn’t make me part of
the diversity problem, and I’ll be watching out for data on the subject.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry>
 <title>Spaced Paragraphs in Word</title>
 <link href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/02/28/Space-paragraphs-in-Word' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='12'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='/ongoing/When/201x/2017/02/28/Space-paragraphs-in-Word#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/02/28/Space-paragraphs-in-Word</id>
 <published>2017-02-28T12:00:00-08:00</published>
 <updated>2017-03-01T00:59:36-08:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Microsoft' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Microsoft' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>The In&#xad;ter&#xad;net is fierce with polemics about one-space-or-two-after-the-period. Bah, lightweight stuff. What about all those poor peo&#xad;ple you see mak&#xad;ing MS Word docs look a lit&#xad;tle more spa&#xad;cious by in&#xad;sert&#xad;ing an ex&#xad;tra emp&#xad;ty line be&#xad;tween para&#xad;graph&#xad;s? There is a bet&#xad;ter way! But the Of&#xad;fice UI (on Mac at least) is heinous, so here&#x2019;s a step-by-step.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>The Internet is fierce with polemics about
one-space-or-two-after-the-period. Bah, lightweight stuff.  What about all
those poor people you see making MS Word docs look a little more spacious by
inserting an extra empty line between paragraphs?
There is a better way!  But the Office UI (on Mac at least) is heinous, so here’s a
step-by-step.</p>
<p>Behold two paragraphs of text, crushed unkindly against each other.</p>
<img src="mwsf0.png" alt="two paragraphs, too close to each other" />
<p>What you want to do is tell Word to henceforth leave a tasteful amount of space between
<em>all</em> your paragraphs, without you having to moronically double-Enter.</p>
<p>You pull down the “Format” menu and select “Style”, for reasons which are
obvious if you understand how Word thinks about the presentation units that it
manages for you.</p>
<img src="mwsf2.png" alt="Format=>Style in Microsoft Word" />
<p>Which gets you this entirely opaque screen.</p>
<img src="mwsf3.png" alt="Style in Microsoft Word" />
<p>Once again, if you were able
to mind-meld with a seasoned Office developer in Redmond, you’d understand
that there’s a reason for each and every little morsel in this smorgasbord.
You may not have thought that “No List” or “Theme Body” were important to your
writing; silly you!
Anyhow, ignore all that crap and just hit the
“Modify…” button in the lower center, to tell Word that you want to fix up the rendering for the
“Normal” style, softly highlighted in the left-side window.</p>
<p>Hm, that soft select suggests that you could hard-select “Normal” by
clicking on it. But don’t, because I can’t be responsible for the
consequences.
Or even double-clicking; I betcha <em>something</em>
happens. I wonder… no, let’s go back to “Modify…”; it’s your
friend.  And people who take a wrong turn in the Office style dialogs are in
Gandalf-and-Mirkwood territory: Leave the path and the
giant spiders are waiting.</p>
<img src="mwsf4.png" alt="Modify Style in Microsoft Word" />
<p>Now we’re getting somewhere. Here are lots of interesting things about the
“Normal” style, which is what you’re using in Word when you’re not using
anything else.  And this screen is just the tip of the iceberg.</p>
<p>It’s helpfully highlighted the style’s name in case you want to change it;
after all, you might not be feeling Normal that day.
But for now we just want some white space.  Many brave women and men have
faced this screen, seen no path forward, and their courage has failed
them. But I’m here to help.  It turns out that what you want is the
bottom-left control labeled “Format”.  Mind you, everything else on this
screen is all about format too; In effect it’s the We Must Go Deeper
menu.</p>
<img src="mwsf5.png" alt="Modify Style Format Pulldown in Microsoft Word" />
<p>Look at that! All the Aristotelian Categories of WYSIWYG, pregnant with ellipses.
Well, except for “Shortcut key…” which you have to feel a little sorry
for, stranded as it is among strangers.</p>
<p>Since we’re trying to space out paragraphs, you might be inspired to think
that the “Paragraph” entry in this pulldown would be your ticket to happiness.  And you’d
be right!</p>
<img src="mwsf6.png" alt="Paragraph Style dialogue in Microsoft Word" />
<p>Really, Word is a pretty-full featured document presentation system, if
you’re up to the dialog-navigation challenges.</p>
<p>Anyhow, it turns out that to achieve the desired effect you use the “Spacing”
group, third from the top<span class='dashes'> —</span> you can see that I’ve
hit the “After” setting which helpfully jumped to a suggested 6 pt of
paragraph separation.  And 6 pt isn’t terrible but I normally prefer a little
less, 5 or 4.  The effect is way more polished than just hitting Enter twice
after each paragraph.  OK, so hit “OK” already.</p>
<img src="mwsf7.png" alt="Back to the Style dialog in Microsoft Word" />
<p>You’re pretty well done, but now you have to escape this maze of
twisty little dialogs, which is not as straightforward as you might think.</p>
<p>A close look reveals that the dialog in front with the “Apply” button
doesn’t actually have focus, the one behind it does.  I’m not sure exactly
how this happens, but it’s really easy to get into a mode where you mash away
at the Apply button and Word just isn’t having it, sneers at your attempts to
Apply your amateur typographical notions. Then you have to bring the other
dialog forward and hit the “OK”.  Or maybe I have that backward.  And it
doesn’t always happen.  But with a
little persistence and after saying “Make It So, Number One” to a variety of
subtly-3D blue buttons, the dialogs will all be gone, leaving your prose
vaulting airily over graceful open space from paragraph to
paragraph.</p>
<img src="mwsf8.png" alt="Separated paragraphs in Microsoft Word" />
<p>OK, 80% of you probably knew this already, and I have learned over the
years that people cheekily double-tapping the “Enter” key between paragraphs
rarely appreciate being told that There Is A Better Way.  Especially when I
start filling their screen with dialogs.</p>
<p>Back to your regularly-scheduled programming.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry>
 <title>Geek Career Paths</title>
 <link href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/02/18/Geek-Career-Paths' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='19'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='/ongoing/When/201x/2017/02/18/Geek-Career-Paths#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/02/18/Geek-Career-Paths</id>
 <published>2017-02-18T12:00:00-08:00</published>
 <updated>2017-02-19T16:47:49-08:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Business' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Business' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>Sup&#xad;pose you&#x2019;re do&#xad;ing tech&#xad;nol&#xad;o&#xad;gy, and like do&#xad;ing tech&#xad;nol&#xad;o&#xad;gy, and your career&#x2019;s go&#xad;ing well, and you find your&#xad;self won&#xad;der&#xad;ing what you&#x2019;re go&#xad;ing to be do&#xad;ing in twen&#xad;ty years. I&#x2019;ve been down sev&#xad;er&#xad;al of the roads you might de&#xad;cide to take, and it oc&#xad;curs to me that talk&#xad;ing them over might amuse and in&#xad;for&#xad;m.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Suppose you’re doing technology, and like doing technology, and your
career’s going well, and you find
yourself wondering what you’re going to be doing in twenty years.
I’ve been down several of the roads you might decide to take,
and it occurs to me that talking them over might amuse and inform.</p>
<p>Thanks are due to
<a href="https://twitter.com/andreleibovici">Andre Leibovici</a>, who tweeted
<a href="https://twitter.com/andreleibovici/status/830099649147002880">Is it
possible to be in a sr. leadership position and still be hands-on w/ tech
&amp; code? For geek leaders out there... how to juggle?</a> and got me
thinking about this.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Q: Should you stay in tech-related work?</h2>
<p>Seriously, this is the most important question.  I know of
knitting-store owners and carpenters and luthiers and microbrewers and doctors
who walked away from tech life.
Their reasons were good: They wanted to engage with life physically,
to get away from rows of desks, to be outside, to be around women.</p>
<p>Me, I was never tempted; I’ve liked computers for their own sake for decades
and still do.  But I’ve watched people do this, and I’m pretty convinced
that if you’re going to, it’s never too late or too early.  When you’re young
you can get by on less, have more energy, and have lots of years to flail
around till something works.  When you’re older, you probably have more money,
which can be used to solve a remarkable variety of problems, and more
experience as to how the world works.</p>
<p>For the purposes of this piece, let’s assume you’re staying on the tech train.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>Q: Should you stay technical?</h2>
<p>The bad news that it’s a lot of work. We’re a
young profession and we’re still working out our best practices, so the ground
keeps changing under you; it doesn’t
get easier as the decades go by.</p>
<p>The good news is that it doesn’t get harder either.  Once you learn to stop
expecting your knowledge to stay fresh, the pace of innovation doesn’t feel to
me like it’s much faster (or slower) now than it was in 1987 or 1997 or 2007.
More good news: The technology gets <em>better</em>.  Seriously, we are so
much better at building software now than we used to be in any of those other
years ending in 7.</p>
<p>And another thing that may not be obvious: It’s not a one-way door.  I
stepped off the technology train, spent years in startup management and
technology evangelism, and climbed back into engineering life without too much
pain.</p>
<p>It hurts me to say this, but there are gender issues here.  There is a
pernicious tendency for smart women to get streamed away from actually doing
technology to, well, almost any of the alternatives I’m going to talk about
below.  I’ve been in the room when it happens: “She’s great with
customers and super-organized, let’s encourage her to look at a management
role.”  Not that there’s anything <em>wrong</em> with a management role, but
the engineering ranks need women too.</p>
<h2 id='p-3'>Q: Should you go into management?</h2>
<p>I tried it, was a CTO and a CEO.  I liked being on the spot for everything
that mattered, and rarely having to wait for someone else to make a
decision.  Also, of course, getting the biggest paycheck.</p>
<p>But I hated lots of things: finding investors and dealing with them,
managing cash-flow, being pulled in a thousand directions every minute,
the really
hard shitty HR problems that get to the top, and never being able to
say anything that wasn’t on-message.  I also disliked the company of my fellow
CEOs, because they are people who can never say anything that’s not
on-message.</p>
<p>A lot of the best executives started out as
engineers.  And there are really no barriers.  In every tech company
I’ve been in, if you’re a competent engineer and also a good communicator, and show
evidence of seeing the bigger picture, then if you tell your boss you’d like to try
management someday, that day may come a lot faster than you expect.</p>
<h2 id='p-11'>Q: Should you go into Product Management?</h2>
<p>FYI: Good product managers are really hard to grow
and hard to hire. So if you combine those technical, business, and communication
skills, you won’t have any trouble finding work.</p>
<p>But it’s probably not a good <em>long-term</em> choice; most companies
don’t have much of a career path for PMs.  That may not be a problem;
many PMs transfer to management or marketing positions
after a while, without obvious strain.</p>
<p>So while it might be a good choice right now, you’re probably not going to
be a PM in twenty years.</p>
<h2 id='p-12'>Q: Should you go into sales?</h2>
<p>I’ve been on a lot of sales calls, and closed a couple of big deals all by
myself, which is one of the most insanely satisfying things you can get paid
for  (and you can get paid a lot).  It’s easy enough to find out; most
technology companies’ salespeople regularly need geek support and well-run
ones are happy to send engineers out on sales calls.  If you like what you
see, give it a try.</p>
<p>Yes, there’s the risk of ending up in <cite>Glengarry Glen Ross</cite>.
And that remorseless pressure to close is implicit in the profession. But
a lot of really successful sales people are ex-engineers; is the remorseless
pressure to ship that much better?</p>
<p>Here’s a hint: All the truly great sales pros I’ve
known have been people people; would genuinely rather hang out and shoot the
shit all day than anything else.  If that’s not you, then probably not.</p>
<h2 id='p-4'>Q: Should you go into marketing?</h2>
<p>Marketing is at the center of everything.  You probably know why you’re
building the technology you’re working on, and what it’s good for,
But it turns out that figuring out who out there needs it, what they’d use it
for, and how to explain it in simple enough terms that an overworked non-geek can get
it quickly, is really <em>really</em> hard.</p>
<p>There’s a range of marketing roles, from tech-oriented ones like “developer
advocate” or “evangelist”, all the way over to full-time business strategist.
Every one of them is accessible in principle to a technical person who wants
to change lanes.</p>
<h2 id='p-6'>Q: Should you go into Venture Capital?</h2>
<p>Please, please don’t.  With the exception of a very few top-tier firms,
it’s a shitty business that delivers a lousy return to its investors.  A large
part of your job consists of saying “no” to people, then watching most of the
people you say “yes” to fail anyhow.</p>
<p>In my view, most of the pathologies that infect the tech sector,
starting with self-absorbedness, arrogance, and lousy diversity, are joined at
the hip with VC culture.</p>
<h2 id='p-5'>Q: Should you work for startups?</h2>
<p>Absolutely, yes. I have, twice.  The best reason is that you’ll get to see
all the different parts of a business up close, how they work, and if you
decide you want to pitch in with something that looks interesting, you may not
encounter much resistance, particularly if you turn out to be good at it.</p>
<p>The white-hot team intensity, the feeling that you and a few others are
moving the world, is just not something you’re going to find elsewhere.</p>
<p>You might make a lot of money, but do bear in mind that most startups fail,
and there are a lot of ways for a startup to succeed where most of the money goes
to the VCs and almost none to foot soldiers.</p>
<h2 id='p-7'>Q: Should you work for a BigCo?</h2>
<p>Yes; you might not like it, but you should try it.  Particularly, in a
well-run company, when you get to see what high-quality marketing and legal
support is like, and what classes of problem can be solved by throwing
money at them, and maybe most of all, how to build systems and processes that
are sustainable in the long term. </p>
<p>The flip-side of that coin is that you’ll likely also see
institutionalized stupidity, toxic politics, and pathological caution. But I
think the rewards make up for it.</p>
<p>I should also point out that you can make serious money working for
a BigCo too, particularly if you get lucky with the share price.  I speak from
experience here.</p>
<p>Finally, suppose you’ve tried managing people and you just don’t like it,
but you still want a senior job.  Most big tech companies have a position
called “Principal Engineer” or “Distinguished Engineer” or some such, which it
usually takes decades to grow into, but is pretty well the ideal
job for someone like me.  You get to work on the most interesting problems and
feel like you’re part of the leadership team, and have the chance to move the
needle.</p>
<p><a href="http://redmonk.com/team/fintan-ryan/">Fintan Ryan</a> of RedMonk
just published
<a href="http://redmonk.com/fryan/2016/12/12/on-the-myth-of-the-10x-engineer-and-the-reality-of-the-distinguished-engineer/?utm_content=buffer5b28c&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_campaign=buffer">On the Myth of the 10X Engineer and the Reality of the Distinguished Engineer</a>,
which I think overstates the wonderfulness of the position, but does hit a few
key points.</p>
<h2 id='p-8'>Q: Should you work for a government?</h2>
<p>Up till maybe five years ago, I would have said “No way, run screaming in
the other direction.”  For decades governments as a matter of policy hired no
software developers and based all their projects on outsourcing, usually
to loathsome blue-suit operations whose core competencies are winning
public-sector bids then cashing in by charging for every ripple coming out of
those classic waterfall projects.</p>
<p>In recent years, led initially by the UK organization now called the
<a href="https://gds.blog.gov.uk/">Government Digital Service</a>,
a few governments have clued into the fact that information
processing is an essential core competence for the public sector, and started
pulling it in-house.</p>
<p>Remember
when the Obama administration wrested control of
<a href="https://www.healthcare.gov/">healthcare.gov</a> out of the hands of
the consultants, aimed a bunch of competent geeks at it, and rescued it?  I’m
thinking that kind of work could be among the most rewarding things you could
load up a technical career with.</p>
<p>There’s a sub-question here: How about a job in the inteligence community?
I’ve never had one, but I’ve sold them technology and worked with them.  They have
the biggest computers and maybe the hardest problems, and I firmly believe
that effective intelligence makes the world a safer place.</p>
<p>But the people I
know in the community always seemed more stressed out and less happy than your
average geek, and I heard persistent grumbling about work-culture problems.  So
I’m not sure I’d recommend that path.</p>
<h2 id='p-13'>Q: Should you work for a non-tech company?</h2>
<p>I can’t help you here very much; never done it.  Since I’ve been working
for AWS I’ve got in face time with a lot of IT people from outside the
geek-o-sphere, and they seem to be pretty happy. But then, the ones I’m talking
to are the ones mixed up in the move to the cloud, which is absolutely the
most interesting single trend in IT these days.</p>
<p>Obviously, you’re probably at slightly higher risk of a
pointy-haired boss who hasn’t the vaguest idea what it is you actually do.</p>
<h2 id='p-9'>Q: Should you be a consultant?</h2>
<p>This is really two questions.  First, should you be an independent
consultant, working for yourself?  I have, and it was OK, and paid pretty
well (although both the startup and the BigCo did better).  You have to be
willing to market yourself aggressively; conference speaking slots work
best, in my experience. Then, after the gig, you have to hassle
your customers to get paid, which really isn’t fun.  Finally, you’re going to
be spending a lot of time on the road.</p>
<p>I had fun, and several remarkably interesting customers.  Two things got on
my nerves. First, you get to work on the hard problems, but you never get to
stick around and ship a product.  Second: A lot of times you end up telling
management exactly the same thing their own smart geeks were telling them, but
they listen to you, not their own people</p>
<p>The second question is, should you go work for a big consulting company?
I’d offer a firm “No”, even though the pay
is good.  These companies work their people insanely hard, and in my opinion, based on
thirty years of observation, charge too much and deliver too little.
They are definitely Part Of The Problem, and you should stay away.</p>
<h2 id='p-10'>Q: Should you work for a nonprofit or charity?</h2>
<p>I never have, and I regret it.  Obviously, this is not a ticket to the 1%,
and I suspect that the technology problems and solutions are pretty
mundane. But I’d hope there would be other, more important, rewards.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry>
 <title>Looking Up</title>
 <link href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/02/19/Looking-Up' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='3'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='/ongoing/When/201x/2017/02/19/Looking-Up#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/02/19/Looking-Up</id>
 <published>2017-02-19T12:00:00-08:00</published>
 <updated>2017-02-19T14:27:59-08:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>Seems like ev&#xad;ery&#xad;one I know is blue and grouchy and an&#xad;gry; can&#x2019;t say as I blame them. But it&#x2019;s time to turn a cor&#xad;ner, be&#xad;cause the future&#x2019;s just as long as ev&#xad;er, and we need joy to face it. Let me see if I can help.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Seems like everyone I know is blue and grouchy and angry; can’t say as I
blame them. But it’s time to turn a corner, because the future’s just as long
as ever, and we need joy to face it.  Let me see if I can help.</p>
<p>Canada’s first few crocuses are up!</p>
<img src="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/02/19/FXT18875.png" alt="2017 Crocuses" />
<p>Yes, I did blog about the spring crocuses in
<a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2003/02/22/Garden">2003</a>,
<a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2004/02/29/FlowerPain">2004</a>,
<a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2005/01/28/Crocuses">2005</a>,
<a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2006/02/05/Crocuses">2006</a>,
<a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2007/02/10/Crocuses">2007</a>,
<a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2008/02/17/First-Crocus-of-the-Year">2008</a>
(<a href="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2008/03/11/Purple-Raindrops">twice!</a>),
<a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2009/02/16/Crocus">2009</a> (<a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2009/03/11/Crocus-Sequence">twice!</a>),
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2010/02/02/Dailyshoot-79">2010</a> (<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2010/02/07/Spring">twice!</a>),
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2011/03/06/Crocus">2011</a>,
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2012/02/26/2012-Crocuses">2012</a>,
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2013/02/12/Every-Year-this-time-Crocuses">2013</a>,
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2014/02/08/N5-Lying-Flowers">2014</a>, and
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2015/01/25/Crocuses-of-2015">2015</a>.
Clearly I need to remediate 2016’s lacklustre performance.</p>
<p>Once again, as I often do, I should echo the question from John Crowley’s awesome
<a href="http://amzn.to/2kX6r6r">Little, Big</a> (seriously, one of the best
books): “What is Brother North-Wind’s secret?” The answer: “If Winter comes,
Spring can’t be far behind.”</p>
<p>This winter, our discontent has been political mostly.  Lots of wars and
lies and pain to be sad about, but most sharply felt: 62,985,106
Americans, about 25.4% of the potential electorate, thought it was
OK to vote for That Man.</p>
<p>I’m sad too.  And about Syria and Brexit and our sick elderly cat and my
children’s foibles and global warming and destructive inequality and the fact
that people still in 2017 think God wants them to kill other people.</p>
<p>But enough of that; today we’re in this blog’s silver-lining department. So
here are a few more things to smile about.</p>
<ul>
<li><p>What with the Women’s March and so on, the angry and disappointed have
learned that they’re not crazy and not alone.</p></li>
<li><p>The explosion of unrest and anger has educated people around the world
as to how non-monolithic America is.</p></li>
<li><p>The proportion of people around the world who’ve realized that
Elections Have Consequences is noticeably higher than a few months
ago.</p></li>
<li><p>Often I hear good new music on the car radio while I’m driving around.
For example, I recommend
<a href="http://amzn.to/2lwXxzq">Touch</a> by
<a href="https://twitter.com/julytalk">July Talk</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>There’s good <em>old</em> music too! The Rolling Stones made a
<a href="http://amzn.to/2kX14nq">pure blues record</a> and it’s not
terrible.</p></li>
<li><p>There are a lot of good books being written.  For example, I recommend
<a href="http://amzn.to/2lxakCb">Do Not Say We Have Nothing</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>There’s a lot of really good stuff on TV.  For example, I recommend
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Expanse_(TV_series)">The
Expanse</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>Look around you; there are good people in the world.</p></li>
<li><p>Well, and another crocus.</p></li>
</ul>
<img src="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/02/19/FXT18876.png" alt="2017 Crocus" />
<div class='caption'><p>I’ll watch the forecast for sunshine once they’ve
opened,<br/>and take some more.</p></div>
<p>Seriously, let’s grant that there are really unhappy trends stinking up
the landscape.  And that if we want to be part of the solution, it’s going to
be a lot of uphill work with, doubtless, downhill slips.  But it’s worth
doing, and for reasons of mental health, and long-term survival, and pure
propaganda, I’m going to try to walk into 2017 with a smile.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry>
 <title>Two AWS Years</title>
 <link href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/02/12/A-couple-AWS-years' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='5'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='/ongoing/When/201x/2017/02/12/A-couple-AWS-years#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/02/12/A-couple-AWS-years</id>
 <published>2017-02-12T12:00:00-08:00</published>
 <updated>2017-02-13T08:13:12-08:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Cloud' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Cloud' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>Wow, it was De&#xad;cem&#xad;ber 2014 when I climbed on board this train. I&#x2019;m sit&#xad;ting in a pret&#xad;ty in&#xad;ter&#xad;est&#xad;ing place and feel I owe the world some re&#xad;portage.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Wow, it was December 2014 when I climbed on board this train.  I’m sitting
in a pretty interesting place and feel I owe the world some reportage.</p>
<p>In terms of what it’s like to work to work here, I don’t have much to add
to
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2015/12/01/One-Amazon-Year">last year’s
write-up</a>.</p>
<p>Since then I’ve got my fingerprints all over two AWS services:
<a href="http://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonCloudWatch/latest/events/WhatIsCloudWatchEvents.html">CloudWatch
Events</a>
and <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/step-functions/">Step Functions</a>.
There are few things as much fun as helping ship something and
watching people start to use it.</p>
<p>If you want opinions on what those products mean and how well they work,
there are lots of blogs out there written by people who are less
biased.</p>
<p>But here’s one amusing sidelight.  When I came to work here I
felt like I was facing a thousand-mile-high wall of technology and knowledge
and experience, and damn little of the stuff I knew felt relevant.  After six
months it was less scary, but I still feel like a
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2011/08/05/Permanoob">Perma-noob</a> much of the
time.
Well, except for the
<a href="https://states-language.net/spec.html">Amazon States
Language</a><span class='dashes'> —</span> they needed a JSON DSL, with a
specification, and a parser inside the service, and (it became obvious) a
<a href="https://github.com/awslabs/statelint">downloadable command-line
version</a>. I smiled, because had this rare feeling of “I know
<em>exactly</em> what needs to be done here, as well as
almost anyone in the world, and how to do it.”  I wonder if
that’ll ever happen again in my whole life.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>What makes me happy</h2>
<p>Turning IT from Capex into Opex.</p>
<p>Writing code that processes billions of messages per week with good
<b>O()</b>-notation behavior.</p>
<p>Working in an almost-entirely-asshole-free environment.</p>
<p>My paycheck.</p>
<p>Hearing about the weird shit people do with the infrastructure we rent
’em.</p>
<p>Working in Vancouver.</p>
<p>Cloud hypergrowth.</p>
<h2 id='p-5'>What makes me scared</h2>
<p>Cloud hypergrowth.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>What makes me unhappy</h2>
<p>Working when it’s nice outside.</p>
<p>Videoconferencing technology.</p>
<p>Male-dominated professions.</p>
<p>I-5 between Vancouver and Seattle.</p>
<h2 id='p-3'>What makes me impressed</h2>
<p>Network design that enables things like VPCs at scale.</p>
<p>Serverless. I’m pretty sure there’s a there there.</p>
<p>Linux. Seriously, no sense of strain after all these years.</p>
<p>IntelliJ.</p>
<p><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/cloudtrail/">CloudTrail</a>. Maybe the most radical AWS service. I can’t
imagine running a serious business without something like it. The combo with
CloudWatch Events makes me smile too.</p>
<h2 id='p-4'>What makes me dubious and cynical</h2>
<p>AI. <i>*gasp*</i> OK, the best implementations can now beat humans at Go and (even more
impressive) reliably distinguish between photos of cats and dogs. But OMG
the hype. My advice: Try linear regression first.</p>
<p>Node and NPM.</p>
<p>Blockchain.</p>
<p>AdTech.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry>
 <title>Super Stifado</title>
 <link href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2015/02/01/Super-Stifado' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='1'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='/ongoing/When/201x/2015/02/01/Super-Stifado#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2015/02/01/Super-Stifado</id>
 <published>2015-02-01T12:00:00-08:00</published>
 <updated>2017-02-05T23:46:39-08:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Food and Drink' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Food and Drink' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>My Su&#xad;per Bowl Stew has be&#xad;come a tra&#xad;di&#xad;tion, so I should share  it. With some tech mag&#xad;ic too. <i>[Up&#xad;dat&#xad;ed again for 2017.]</i></div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>My Super Bowl Stew has become a tradition, so I should share
it.  With some tech magic too. <i>[Updated again for 2017.]</i></p>
<p>What happened was, eight years ago
<a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2007/02/05/Superbowl">Prince played the
Superbowl</a> and I made a Stifado for guests, a Greek version of a fairly
straightforward beef (or rabbit) stew distinguished by heavy oregano.  I got
the idea from a fellow-employee’s piece on the late lamented
blogs.sun.com.</p>
<p>I later refined the recipe from with ideas from another foodie site, also
now vanished,
<cite>A Spoonful of Sugar</cite> (I think), dedicated to stews and
suchlike.</p>
<p>Anyhow, this morning two miracles happened; I was poking around the
Internet not liking any of the Stifado recipes, when Lauren suggested looking
in the Wayback Machine, and there it is:
<a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20070208191708/http://blogs.sun.com/paulhu/entry/beef_stifado">Beef
Stifado by Paul Humphreys</a>. (Still out there, Paul?)</p>
<p>The next miracle was
when on impulse I hit “print” on my Android<span class='dashes'> —</span> first
time I’ve ever done that<span class='dashes'> —</span> it auto-magically found the
network printer in the basement and Just Worked.  For making a big messy stew,
you definitely want to read the recipe off paper not a screen.</p>
<p>OK, here’s Tim’s improved version of Paul’s stew as filtered through
several other minds and a handful of Super Bowls</p>
<ol>
<li><p>This recipe starts with 2lb (a kg or so) of stewing beef. My butcher
cuts them too big, so I have to slice them up a little further. The first step
is to brown the meat in a little oil. I mean <em>really brown it</em>, with
dark brown scorch marks here and there.</p></li>
<li><p><i>[2017 update]</i> I make the stew in a big old
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Le_Creuset">Le Creuset</a> oval
enameled iron thing, and I used to brown the meat in there too, which left its
floor a
blackened hell of baked-on gravy. So this time I did the browning in the nice
well-cured cast-iron frying pan instead; much less washing-up!</p></li>
<li><p>Then you dump in a couple of fair-sized onions,
chopped, doesn’t need to be too fine, sautee them till they’re soft and
perfumey.</p></li>
<li><p>Toss in a big can of tomatoes. Crushed or sliced or whatever,
doesn’t matter much.</p></li>
<li><p>Then take all the garlic from wherever you store the garlic, peel and
slice and toss in.  This needs to be really a lot of garlic.</p></li>
<li><p>Also add maybe a quarter of one of those little cans of tomato
paste.</p></li>
<li><p>Also, the juice of a lemon.</p></li>
<li><p>Finally, a tablespoon of sugar, a quarter cup of red
wine vinegar, and a generous slosh of real red wine. Entertain yourself with
the rest.  Oh, and some salt.</p></li>
<li><p>Mix all this up and sprinkle the top with oregano. Dried oregano not
fresh; you want that sharpness of flavor.</p></li>
<li><p>Cook it for a long time.  I had it in the oven by noon and we ate
during the fourth quarter of the ballgame.  This will make your house smell
great.</p></li>
<li><p>About a half-hour before you’re going to eat, stir in a shallot or two
per person who’s going to be eating, and give the stew a second sprinkling of
oregano.  The soft shallots are a real treat in your bowl of stew.</p></li>
</ol>
<p>We always serve it with home-made cornbread and a big salad, but I think
you could pair lots of other things successfully.</p>
<p>Also, they should have given the ball to Lynch or called a Wilson run around
the left.  But since everyone on the planet was thinking that too, probably
that little pass was piece of offensive innovation.  Well, it would have been
if it’d worked.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry>
 <title>Time Machine Completed the Backup</title>
 <link href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/01/31/Synology-Time-Machine-Failure' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='5'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='/ongoing/When/201x/2017/01/31/Synology-Time-Machine-Failure#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/01/31/Synology-Time-Machine-Failure</id>
 <published>2017-01-31T12:00:00-08:00</published>
 <updated>2017-01-31T22:41:43-08:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Storage' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Storage' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>Re&#xad;cent&#xad;ly, I <a href='/ongoing/When/201x/2016/12/20/Network-backup'>ac&#xad;quired a Synol&#xad;o&#xad;gy DiskS&#xad;ta&#xad;tion</a>  and wired up a nice com&#xad;fort&#xad;ing <a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_Machine_(macOS)'>Time Ma&#xad;chine</a>-to-<a href='http://amzn.to/2kPdUo9'>Synol&#xad;o&#xad;gy</a>-to-<a href='https://aws.amazon.com/s3'>S3</a>-to-<a href='https://aws.amazon.com/glacier/'>Glacier</a>   back&#xad;up da&#xad;ta flow. But then I  start&#xad;ed to see &#x201c;Time Ma&#xad;chine couldn&#x2019;t com&#xad;plete the backup&#x201d; with some&#xad;thing  about &#x201c;could not be ac&#xad;cessed (er&#xad;ror 21)&#x201d;. Here&#x2019;s how it got fixed.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Recently, I
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2016/12/20/Network-backup">acquired
a Synology DiskStation</a> and wired up a nice comforting
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_Machine_(macOS)">Time
Machine</a>-to-<a href="http://amzn.to/2kPdUo9">Synology</a>-to-<a href="https://aws.amazon.com/s3">S3</a>-to-<a href="https://aws.amazon.com/glacier/">Glacier</a>
backup data flow. But then I
started to see “Time Machine couldn’t complete the backup” with something
about “could not be accessed (error 21)”.  Here’s how it got fixed.</p>
<img src="blurgs.png" alt="Time Machine problem" class="inline" />
<p>[This piece placed here to attract search-engine attention and, with luck,
help someone else dig out. If you’re feeling public-spirited, toss in a couple
links for visibility’s sake.]</p>
<p>I was tempted to give up, but the thing was working fine for my wife, who
however was not yet on Sierra; there was some Twitter rumbling about Sierra and
Synology having relationship problems.</p>
<p>With the aid of Google and Twitter, I eventually did all these things, and
finally data started flowing again.  Perhaps they are not all necessary.</p>
<ol>
<li><p>After a tweeted squeal for help, Saul Tannenbaum
(<a href="https://twitter.com/stannenb">@stannenb)</a>
and Shazron Abdullah (<a href="https://twitter.com/shazron">@shazron</a>)
suggested installing
the
<a href="https://www.synology.com/en-global/beta">Synology beta</a>, and
connecting over SMB not AFP.  Because SMB is the new shiny, amirite?</p></li>
<li><p>Also per @stannenb, poked around in the Synology menus (Control
Panel>File Services>Service Discovery) to enable “Bonjour Time Machine
broadcast via SMB”. Uh huh.</p></li>
<li><p>At some point before the backups started failing, I’d seen a message
about a Time Machine verification problem; Googling that led me to Jonas’
<a href="http://jd-powered.net/notes/fixing-your-time-machine-backup">Fixing
your Time Machine backup</a>, which talks you through mounting the ”sparse
bundle” and using the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fsck">fsck</a> hammer.  Last time I
used fsck it was in a different millennium.
Thanks, Jonas.  Like he said, it ain’t fast, and the use of a wired network is
indicated.</p></li>
</ol>
<p>Of course, a civilian would have been dead in the water, and I should be
mad at either Apple or Synology, or the pair of them for not playing nice.
But at the moment, I’m so relieved to have this working that I’m not.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry>
 <title>Shooter as Tabula Rasa</title>
 <link href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/01/30/Whose-Killer' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='2'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='/ongoing/When/201x/2017/01/30/Whose-Killer#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/01/30/Whose-Killer</id>
 <published>2017-01-30T12:00:00-08:00</published>
 <updated>2017-01-30T23:58:13-08:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Politics' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Politics' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Life Online' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Life Online' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>Last night I ac&#xad;ci&#xad;den&#xad;tal&#xad;ly came face to face with Twit&#xad;ter hor&#xad;ror, a very pale re&#xad;flec&#xad;tion of larg&#xad;er real-life hor&#xad;ror, but still jar&#xad;ring. What hap&#xad;pened was, some&#xad;one shot up a Qu&#xe9;bec Ci&#xad;ty mosque. For a few hours no&#xad;body knew who&#x2019;d done the shoot&#xad;ing, and that ab&#xad;sence of iden&#xad;ti&#xad;ty be&#xad;came a blank can&#xad;vas which the Net&#x2019;s trolls paint&#xad;ed with their shit-colored dream&#xad;s.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Last night I accidentally came face to face with Twitter horror, a very
pale reflection of larger real-life horror, but still jarring.
What happened was, someone
shot up a Québec City mosque.  For a few hours nobody knew who’d done the
shooting, and that absence of identity became a blank canvas which the Net’s
trolls painted with their shit-colored dreams.</p>
<p>I got interested in the story and like everyone else was curious who the
bad guys were.  Watched Twitter because that’s what you do when news is
hanging fire. Tuned in the
<a href="http://ici.radio-canada.ca/">Radio Canada</a> (French-language)
livestream of the 1:45AM Eastern Time press conference by the Québec Premier,
the Québec city mayor, and the police chief, which was emotional and had the
sad facts about deaths and injuries, but didn’t ID the shooters.</p>
<p>I thought it couldn’t hurt to get the straight story out to the
non-Francophone world and
<a href="https://twitter.com/timbray/status/825959894222147584">tweeted</a>
“Quebec premier, Quebec city mayor, and police chief live press conf now,
declining to say who attackers were.
<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/saintefoy?f=tweets&amp;vertical=news&amp;src=hash">#SainteFoy</a>”.</p>
<p>That hashtag, based on the street where the mosque is, seemed the hottest
one late yesterday.  I’d glanced in, finding mostly sorrow and solidarity, but
after I became part of it looked closer and started feeling sick.
Because it was obvious that a whole lot of people were hoping really
hard that the shooter was Their Personal Other.  Robyn Urback brought a nice
turn of phrase, on the CBC:
<a href="http://www.cbc.ca/news/opinion/mosque-shooting-narrative-1.3958357">How to make a tragedy fit your desired narrative</a>.</p>
<p>Except for a lot of people weren’t just hoping that the killer was (a) a
crazed Islamist or (b) a crazed Trumpkin, they were announcing it
proactively. The dreary litany of 21st-century exalted ignorance:
Islamofascism, Kellie Leitch, Barack <i>Hussein</i> y’know, “They were Syrian
refugees!”, “political correctness”, TrumpTrumpTrump, alt-right, Liberal
apologists, yadda yadda fucking yadda.
So many of them, so little thought, so much anger, so much fear. Twitter
trolling, it’s so easy to ignore when it’s not in your timeline.</p>
<p>I was going to copy in some of the more deplorable tweets, but
then I’d be part of the problem, wouldn’t I?
But let’s make one exception:</p>
<img src="jerk.png" alt="A Jerk" />
<p>This is the white supremacist who was punched out on live TV the other day
in Washington. He had some other remarks on the incident.  I hope he comes to
Canada real soon now.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>What actually happened</h2>
<p>The shooter was a
<a href="http://www.theglobeandmail.com/news/national/quebec-city-mosque-attack-suspect-known-for-right-wing-online-posts/article33833044/"><i>pure laine</i> Québecois</a>, given to social-media mooning
at alt-right icons specifically including Marine Le Pen.  Let’s not
generalize; life’s too short to walk around in daily fear of either jihadis or
fascist-wannabes, and you’re way more likely to get hit by a bus.</p>
<p>The second person arrested is actually
<a href="http://www.lapresse.ca/actualites/dossiers/attentat-a-quebec/201701/30/01-5064556-mohamed-belkhadir-pour-eux-quelquun-qui-fuit-cest-un-suspect.php?utm_source=dlvr.it&amp;utm_medium=twitter">an interesting story</a>,
a random Muslim engineering student who was shoveling the mosque’s snow during
the shooting, called 911 and was giving first aid when the cops arrived waving
guns. He (not unreasonably) panicked and ran, and they (not
unreasonably) chased him down.  No hard
feelings either side.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>A lesson</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/breaking-news-consumers-handbook-pdf/">The Breaking News Consumer’s Handbook</a>;
go read it. Right, as usual, in every particular.  And if you don’t know
what’s going on, shut the fuck up about it.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry>
 <title>The Women&#x2019;s March</title>
 <link href='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/01/22/Womens-March' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='3'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='/ongoing/When/201x/2017/01/22/Womens-March#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/01/22/Womens-March</id>
 <published>2017-01-22T12:00:00-08:00</published>
 <updated>2017-01-22T23:00:47-08:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Politics' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Politics' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>Just like ev&#xad;ery&#xad;one else I have a the&#xad;o&#xad;ry about What It Mean&#xad;s, but I al&#xad;so have a sto&#xad;ry and a cool pic&#xad;ture to il&#xad;lus&#xad;trate.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Just like everyone else I have a theory about What It Means, but I also
have a story and a cool picture to illustrate.</p>
<img src="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/01/22/FXT18739.png" alt="Vancouver’s Roots ‘N’ Wings choir performing on Jan 21, 2017" />
<p>We go to a few choir concerts, since <a href="http://laurenwood.org/">my
wife</a> sings in one and is part of that social network.  On January 21st in
a two-choir show, the second half featured
<a href="http://www.songroots.ca/choirs/roots-n-wings">Roots ‘N’ Wings</a>, an
all-women ensemble.  They opened with just a few singers on stage, then the
rest came up the aisles, singing
<a href="http://civilrightssongs.blogspot.ca/2014/11/aint-gonna-let-nobody-turn-me-around.html">Ain’t Gonna Let Nobody Turn Me Around</a>
(one of the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freedom_Songs">Freedom Songs</a>), some
with the hats, some with signs.</p>
<p>The crowd came alive, on their feet, clapping and yelling, singing along.
The choir fed on it and five minutes of pretty pure ecstasy ensued.  My heart
was instantly full.</p>
<p>Earlier that day, my wife and daughter were in the
<a href="http://www.straight.com/news/859136/photos-thousands-vancouverites-flock-downtown-support-womens-march-washington">local
march</a>; I was proud of them.  I didn’t go because I wanted to be part of
those powerful sea-of-women’s-faces visuals by not being in it; anyhow
someone had to clean up and make dinner.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>What the march meant</h2>
<p>I think it’s obvious.  A bunch of reasonable people, led by women, needed
to shout out and reassure each other that they weren’t crazy because they were
horrified at a <i>nouveau regime</i> that’s crude, threatening,
ignorant, oligarchic, reactionary,
childish, corrupt, bigoted, thin-skinned, offensive, and oozes
appallingly bad taste.</p>
<p>That’s about all the marchers had in common; the hardass rhetoric
coming off the main stage was interesting and had its moments, but I bet very
few of the marchers have even heard the word “intersectional”.  Likely
nobody will remember the rhetoric, but everyone will remember the clever
signage, massed pink, glowing faces, and astonishing absence  of violence or
vandalism.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>Hall of shame</h2>
<ul>
<li><p>The new management of the Executive Branch of the United States
Government.</p></li>
<li><p>Twitter, for studding the
<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WomensMarch?src=hash">#WomensMarch</a>
stream with deplorable hate-spewing trolls; they’re still there now.  I mean,
really, <em>Fuck Twitter</em>.</p></li>
<li><p>Those trolls.  My quip: They were grumpy because their Mom
was off marching and couldn’t fix a sandwich for them and bring it down to the
basement.</p>
</li></ul>
<h2 id='p-3'>Thanks!</h2>
<p>For that much-needed reassurance that it’s perfectly OK to have strong
negative feelings over behavior which is
crude, threatening, ignorant, oligarchic, reactionary,
childish, corrupt, bigoted, thin-skinned, offensive, and oozes
appallingly bad taste.</p>
<h2 id='p-4'>What next?</h2>
<p>I dunno.  Nor does anyone else. In the United States, the forces of decency
and sanity suffer from a leadership vacuum.  You can get along without a
coherent ideology, but you need someone to rally around and vote for, and I
don’t see who.</p>
<p>For the next few years, resisting the the hamfisted guttersnipes of the GOP
will be useful and reasonably rewarding<span class='dashes'> —</span> the
evidence suggests they lack the competence to get much done.
But America needs an alternative.</p>
<p>Anyhow, thank you to the Women’s Marchers; I know I needed the
reassurance.  You’re not crazy. I’m not crazy.</p>
</div></content></entry>

</feed>

---

feed.format:         atom
feed.title:          ongoing by Tim Bray
feed.subtitle:       ongoing fragmented essay by Tim Bray
feed.url:            https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/
feed.feed_url:       https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/ongoing.atom
feed.updated_local:  >>> DateTime.new( 2017, 5, 23, 11, 55, 3, '-7' )
feed.updated:        >>> DateTime.new( 2017, 5, 23, 11, 55, 3, '-7' ).utc

feed.generator.name:   Generated from XML source code using Perl, Expat, Emacs, Mysql, Ruby, Java, and ImageMagick.  Industrial-strength technology, baby.
feed.generator.url:    /misc/Colophon

feed.authors.size:      >>> 1
feed.authors[0].name:   Tim Bray
feed.authors[0].url:	  >>> nil
feed.authors[0].email:	>>> nil


feed.items[0].title:     Rock Surprise
feed.items[0].url:       https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/05/20/Rock-Surprise
feed.items[0].id:        https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2017/05/20/Rock-Surprise
feed.items[0].published_local: >>> DateTime.new( 2017, 5, 20, 12,  0, 0, '-7' )
feed.items[0].published:       >>> DateTime.new( 2017, 5, 20, 12,  0, 0, '-7' ).utc
feed.items[0].updated_local:   >>> DateTime.new( 2017, 5, 21, 11, 13, 0, '-7' )
feed.items[0].updated:         >>> DateTime.new( 2017, 5, 21, 11, 13, 0, '-7' ).utc
